<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="34"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN



                               PSYCHOLOGY






                                          LEVEL 1












         Program Performance Profile




















                        AREA II. FACULTY]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN



                               PSYCHOLOGY






                                          LEVEL 1









         Program Performance Profile












                           AREA II. FACULTY











             PARAMETER C.

             FACULTY ADEQUACY AND

             LOADING]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[I.            SYSTEMS-INPUTS AND




                         PROCESS









            The institution has approved



                    policies/guideline on Faculty




                    Workload by the University



                    BOR including institutional



                    policies or Equivalent




                    Teaching Load (ETL).]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Specific Policies and Guidelines on Faculty Workload
                           The workload system shall be implemented by the University in line with the
                   guidelines on faculty workload policies and regulations by CHED. The current
                   faculty workload system may be revised or totally replaced upon approval of the
                   Board.

                           The workload system concerns only the instruction function and related
                   activities of the academic teaching staff of Cavite State University. This was
                   finalized on 14 July 2000 incorporating the comments/suggestions of the University
                   Administrative Council during its 03 July 2000 meeting. Amendments and revisions
                   were again made in December 2002 and May 2007 for the following purposes,
                   among others: define credit units for other activities left to the discretion of the
                   College/Campus Dean, specify the mode of payment for overload teaching and
                   overtime teaching; and suggest source of funds for such payment.

                           Section 1. Coverage. This set of guidelines covers all CvSU faculty
                   members, whether permanent, temporary, or contractual teachers reporting on full
                   time.

                                     a. At the beginning of each school year, before the start of
                                         regular    classes, the college/campus deans shall require
                                         the members of    their faculty to decide whether to be on full-
                                         time teaching,    research or extension, provided that the
                                         needs of instruction are satisfied first and does not lead to
                                         extra hiring of personnel.

                                     It should be noted, however, that although faculty members are
                              classified as full-time teachers, they are still required to conduct either
                              research or extension activities on top of their teaching loads. The list of
                              those on full-time teaching shall be submitted immediately to the office of
                              the Vice President for Academic Affairs (OVPAA) while those on full-time
                              research or extension shall be endorsed by OVPAA to the Office of the
                              Vice President for Research and Development. For efficient allocation of
                              funds, tentative computation of faculty workload for instruction shall be
                              submitted to OVPAA one week, at the latest, before the start of classes
                              in each semester.


                                     a. Faculty members with academic ranks who opt for full–time
                                         research or extension shall be required to teach minimum of
                                         (9) contact hours per week.

                                     b. Credit unit load of faculty members on full–time research or
                                         extension shall be covered by a separate research and
                                         extension workload system of the University.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Section 2. Maximum Workload and Overload Compensation


                                   The maximum regular teaching load of an academic full – time
                           teaching staff without administrative and supervisory assignment in any
                           given semester shall be 18 teaching hours (TCH) per week. (TCH) and
                           equivalent WL units shall be reduced to 18 and 25, respectively effective
                           First Semester, AY 2004 – 2005 depending on availability of funds). For
                           purposes of overload pay, this is equivalent to the maximum of 25
                           instruction workload (WL) credit units

                 a.  The regular workload of full–time teaching staff in a given  semester      shall
                     include only those related to instruction, administrative assignments and other
                     services duly supported by designations issued by the Office of the President of
                     the University (OUP) as recommended by the vice president concerned.

                 b.  Faculty members who opt to be on full-time teaching but who conduct important
                     projects under the priority commodity thrusts of the University shall earn credit
                     units for those projects based on the guidelines for  research  and   extension
                     workload. This credit unit shall be added to  instruction workload provided that
                     these credit units are not credited on full-time research.


                 c.  The final report on faculty workload, including the summary thereof, shall be
                     submitted to the office of the  Vice   President   for  Academic    Affairs  for
                     consolidation    within the final examination period of every semester.


                 d.  An academic staff who is unable to reach the maximum teaching load per week
                     shall be required to teach other courses in other units of the University and/or
                     render    other services deemed necessary as recommended by the Vice
                     President for Academic Affairs and approved by the University President in order
                     to reach the mandatory 40-hour service per week required of all government
                     personnel. In no case, however, shall the conduct of other services lead to hiring
                     of additional part-time or full-  time faculty member. Hiring will only be done
                     when all faculty members are fully loaded at 18 TCH each per week. Exemptions
                     to the required 18 TCH, are faculty members with management and supervisory
                     designations specified. The assigning of such other services shall be endorsed by
                     the Vice President of Academic Affairs for approval by the University President.


                 e.  In case faculty members carrying the full load of 18 TCH are given extra teaching
                     assignment scheduled outside the official time, such assignment shall be covered
                     by a job order in order for the faculty member to receive   equitable
                     remuneration.


                 f.  The detailed guidelines for faculty workload system shall be prepared, reviewed
                     and revised periodically by the Academic Council taking into account the policies
                     listed above.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[II.  IMPLEMENTATION









            The program’s faculty




                    workload system includes the



                    administrative and other




                    quasi assignments with



                    equivalent teaching load



                    (ETL) and its process of




                    equitable and fair



                    distribution of workload]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[II.  IMPLEMENTATION









            Adherence to the provisions




                    of the approved



                    policies/guidelines on Faculty




                    Workload]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[II.  IMPLEMENTATION









            Compatibility of




                    specializations/experience on



                    teaching assignments.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Faculty Profile



        The faculty profile of Faculty of Department of

        Arts and Sciences under Psychology is shown


        below:]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[III.  OUTCOMES









            There is congruence of



                    faculty loading as evident in




                    the compliance of faculty



                    members to all academic




                    policies such as timely



                    submission of required



                    academic reports.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Classroom Observation Report]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[IV.  BEST PRACTICES









            No faculty has more than six



                    hours of continuous




                    teaching.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[IV.  BEST PRACTICES









            Faculty schedule has time for



                    course subject preparations,




                    recording of student’s



                    outputs, and other




                    instruction-related workload.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[IV.  BEST PRACTICES









            The faculty has proper



                    distribution of teaching load




                    in accordance to their subject



                    specialization.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[IV.  BEST PRACTICES









            Though the faculty members are



                    loaded with a high number of



                    teaching hours and preparations.


                    They could still manage to



                    divide their time productively



                    and could still check test papers



                    and student outputs as well as



                    perform their lateral tasks


                    assigned by the higher



                    authorities.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[IV.  BEST PRACTICES









            The faculty members also



                    actively participate and




                    support the University and



                    college activities voluntarily.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[IV.  BEST PRACTICES









            Faculty members actively



                    participate in research and




                    extension activities.]]></page></pages></Search>